# Juliano Daniel Marcelino, M.Sc. **Full Stack Freelance Business Analyst**

### **Profile**

I started my career in IT infrastructure and customer support, since then adding value in almost 30 years of IT Mgmt/Gov, teaching and consulting across worldwide companies experience.

In the last years I've been increasing hard skills both in software development and technologies, currently more dedicated to Flutter, Python, JS, using Docker and other magic tools, as well in agile methodologies and lean IT. On the other hand, the main soft skills are ethics, organization, QC-Story, teamwork, communication, negotiation and flexibility.

### **Experience**

02/2013 - ongoing Uniasselvi Group

In postgraduate and undergraduate, taught person and remote, as well as orientation of bachelor and MBA thesis in technology, engineering, education and correlative disciplines.

⊞09/2019 - 02/2021 ♥ SENAI/SC - Jaraguá do Sul Undergraduate and professional teaching professor.

07/2015 - 04/2019 👽 Catholic University Center Santa Catarina Professor in person and distance learning courses in Bachelor of Information Systems, Software Engineering, Analysis and Systems Development, as Administration and Production Engineering.

Extension and postgraduate professor.

□09/2011 - 02/2013 ♥ Delinea Education Technology

Content professor and technical writer.

02/2009 - 02/2012 SENAI/SC – Jaraguá do Sul

IT and Business Management Specialist, professor, content, tutor and monitor in distance learning, coordinator of the computer architecture and operating systems laboratory.

2008 - 2009 FCJ – Cenecista College of Joinville Professor in Administration and Software Development.

2008 - 2009 CEDB – Dom Bosco Educational Center Educator in vocational training courses in IT and Administration.

2007 - 2008 INPG - National Postgraduate Institute Assistant professor and educational consultant.

2007 - 2008 SoftExpert Automation

Project manager at corporate management systems and consultant in BPM tools, Project Management, BSC, SWOT, KPI, competence management, quality and strategy applications.

2003 - 2006 Datasul/NeoGrid

Consultant and project management in ERP, CRM, B2B, B2C, e/c-Commerce, VMI, JIT, forecast, kanban, and SCI.



# Life Philosophy

I help people (and companies) to solve problems. "There is no one so expert with nothing to learn, and there no one so poor with nothing to teach."

# Keep in touch



+55 (47) 99199-4901

Jaraguá do Sul - SC - Brazil ojmarcelino

ojmarcelino

### Certifications

Kanban Foundation (KIKF)

2020 CertiProf

Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SPFC)

□ 2010 © Cisco Networking Academy

Cisco Certified Network Instructor

### **Education**

UniSociesc Masters of Science in Production Engineering, with emphasis on Lean IT.

2012 Uniasselvi MBA in Teaching to Higher Education.

2008 **INPG** MBA (pending diploma) in Project Management.

2007 Univille Bachelor in Information Systems.

### Languages (CEFR standards)

pt\_PT C2 C2 C1 C1 C2 C2 C2 C1 C1 C2 us\_EN pt\_BR Native language **B1** Equivalent

# Juliano Daniel Marcelino, M.Sc. Analista de Negócios Full Stack Freelance

#### Perfil

Iniciei minha carreira em TI na área de infraestrutura e atendimento ao usuário, e desde então venho agregando valor em quase 30 anos de experiência em IT Gov/IT Mgmt, docência e consultoria em empresas de âmbito internacional.

Nos últimos anos, venho incrementando hard skill tanto em desenvolvimento e tecnologias, atuando mais em Flutter, Python, JS, usando Docker e outras ferramentas mágicas, como também metodologias ágeis e TI enxuta (Mestrado em Lean IT e certificações Scrum e Kanban. Nas soft skills, ética, organização, MASP, trabalho em equipe, comunicação, negociação e flexibilidade.

Atualmente tenho focado em desenvolvimento e deixado a docência de lado, me voltando só para tecnologias e código.

### **Experiência**



Tanto na graduação quanto pós, distancial ou presencial, lecionei e orientei inúmeros TCC e disciplinas, nas áreas de educação, engenharia, administração, análise e desenvolvimento de sistemas e outras áreas correlatas.

- 09/2019 02/2021 SENAI/SC Jaraguá do Sul Graduação e formação profissional, em várias cadeiras no curso de Sistemas para Internet e outros cursos.
- 07/2015 04/2019 Centro Universitário Católica de SC Professor em cursos presenciais e distanciais nas áreas de Sistemas de Informação, Engenharia de Software, Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas, Administração e Engenharia.
- 09/2012 12/2013 Anhanguera Educacional Professor de Pós Graduação e Extensão.
- 09/2011 02/2013 Delinea Tecnologias Educacionais

  Professor conteudista e escritor técnico.
- © SENAI/SC Jaraguá do Sul Especialista em TI e Gestão, professor, tutor, monitor e conteudista em EaD, coordenador do laboratório de Arquitetura de Computadores e Sistemas Operacionais.
- 2008 2009 FCJ Cenecista College of Joinville Professor de Administração e Análise e Desenvolvimento.
- 2008 2009 CEDB Centro Educacional Dom Bosco Educador em treinamentos nos cursos de TI e Administração.
- 2007 2008 INPG Instituto Nacional de Pós Graduação Professor assistente e consultor educacional.
- 2007 2008 SoftExpert Informática
  Gerente de Projetos de sistemas corporativos, e consultoria em
  implantação de BPM, Gestão de Projetos, BSC, SWOT, KPI, gestão por
  competências, qualidade e planejamento estratégico.



### Filosofia de vida

Eu ajudo pessoas (e empresas) a resolver problemas. "Não há ninguém tão grande que não tenha nada a aprender, e nem tão pequeno que não tenha nada a ensinar."

#### Contato

juliano@jmarcelino.com.br
 +55 (47) 99199-4901

Jaraguá do Sul - SC - Brazil

ojmarcelino ojmarcelino

# Certificações

© CertiProf
Scrum Foundations Professional
Certificate (SPFC)

2010 Academia Cisco
Cisco Certified Network Instructor

# Educação

Bacharel em Sistemas de Informação..

# Idiomas (padrão QECR)

pt\_PT C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
us\_EN C2 C2 C1 C1 C2
pt\_BR Lingua materna
Equivalente ao B1